# MATT JONES

m.r.jones@live.co.uk  $\diamond$  mattjones.wales  $\diamond$  LinkedIn

#### PERSONAL SUMMARY

Full-stack software engineer with 6 years of experience working in agile teams. Technical experience includes extensive work with React and building RESTFul microservices. A strong believer in XP practices with an emphasis on collaboration, feedback, and user-focused development. Experience with mentoring junior developers.

## **SKILLS**

Frontend Typescript, React, NextJS, Cypress, Jest, Svelte/SvelteKit, Tailwindcss, Less, Webpack, Vite

Backend Kotlin, Spring Boot, Java, JUnit, Keycloak, Node.js, Python, Elasticsearch

Developer Tools Git, ConcourseCI, Kubernetes, GCP, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, Grafana, Pormetheus, Docker, Terrafor

#### EXPERIENCE

Boclips, Full Stack Engineer, London, UK/Remote

Nov 2018 - Dec 2023  $\cdot$  4 years 1 month

Working for a London ed-tech startup in an XP team, providing a media streaming platform through various integrations. Spent the last 3 months as a tech lead

Kotlin, TypeScript, React, Kubernetes, GCP, Elasticsearch, DDD, TDD, XP

- Built and maintained full-stack applications. React & Typescript webapps, backed by Spring Boot microservices implemented in Kotlin, all orchestrated by Kubernetes on GCP.
- Collaborated with the PM, UX designers, and engineering leads to shape delivery and implementation plans.
- Managed technical debt to ensure it was addressed in a sustainable manner.
- Modernized tech stack, whilst migrating code and customers away from a legacy system.
- Improved web application load times using various techniques, such as caching and code splitting.
- Managed and mentored a junior engineer.
- Conducted initial technical interviews to hire engineers across all levels.
- Organised weekly "Lunch and Learn" sessions for the engineering team to promote knowledge sharing.
- Facilitated (including company-wide) retrospectives to evaluate and improve team processes.
- Practiced pair programming, TDD, and all other XP fun.

### Hawk-Eye Innovations, Software Engineer, Remote

Oct 2017 - Jun 2018 · 9 months

Working in Hawk-Eye's SMARTData team, developed data-driven web technologies and real-time broadcasting graphics engines in an agile environment.

Java, Spring Boot, HTML5, React, TypeScript

- Optimised an HTML5 data-driven broadcast graphics engine for FIVB's Volleyball Nations League
- Enhanced an interactive timeline for use alongside Hawk-Eye's core replay software
- Played a significant role in sprint planning, backlog prioritization, and pull request reviews

Hawk-Eye Innovations, Junior Software Engineer, Basingstoke

Jun 2015 - Aug 2016  $\cdot$  1 year 3 months

I was a junior software developer working in Hawk-Eye's replay technology team, working on projects related to some of the world's top sporting events. Responsibilities included delivering new features and general bug fixing.

#### **EDUCATION**

## BSc (Hons) in Computer Science, Bath University

2013-2017

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science with second-class honours first division